Register of the Carl Gershman papers, 1961-1984
Hoover Institution Archives
- INCREMENTAL MATERIALS, 1961-1984 (Boxes 15-31)
  - SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1969-1980 (Boxes 16-17)
    - "The Democrats, the Republicans, and Israel,", 1971 (Box-folder 16: 32)
    - "The New Left and Israel 4 Years After,", 1971 (Box-folder 16: 33)
    - "The New Left and the Palestinians: A Radical View,", 1971 (Box-folder 16: 34)
    - Review of Mordecai S. Chertoff, ed., The New Left and the Jews, Jewish Frontier, 1971 November (Box-folder 16: 35)
    - "Rowland Evans' Complaint," Survey, 1971 (Box-folder 16: 36)
    - "Senator Henry M. Jackson: Israel's Dependable Friend,", 1971 (Box-folder 16: 37)
    - "Henry Jackson and Jewish Youth,", 1972 (Box-folder 16: 38)
    - "Jackson and the Liberal Coalition,", 1972 (Box-folder 16: 39)
    - "Munich: Terror and Democracy,", 1972 (Box-folder 16: 40)
    - "Neither Jewish Radicals Nor Radical Jews," The Jewish Digest, 1972 January (Box-folder 16: 41)
    - "The New World Balance,", 1972 (Box-folder 16: 42)
    - "A Perspective on Young Jews,", 1972 (Box-folder 16: 43)
    - "Do the Arabs Really Want Peace?,", 1974 (Box-folder 16: 44)
    - "The Middle East: American Choices in a Troubled Area,", 1974 (Box-folder 16: 45)
    - Review of Stephen D. Isaacs, Jews and American Politics, Commentary, 1974 December (Box-folder 16: 46)
    - "Socialism Today,", 1974 (Box-folder 16: 47)
    - "Abe Raskin's Catch 22,", 1975 (Box-folder 16: 48)
    - "The American Labor Movement: Ally of Israel,", 1975 (Box-folder 16: 49)
    - "Bloodbaths and Dominoes,", 1975 (Box-folder 16: 50)
    - "The Fruits of Appeasement,", 1975 (Box-folder 16: 51)
    - "A Good Beginning,", 1975 (Box-folder 16: 52)
    - "Moynihan and the Politics of Ideas,", 1975 (Box-folder 16: 53)
    - Draft statement on the international situation, 1976 (Box-folder 16: 54)
    - "The Liberals and Angola,", 1976 (Box-folder 16: 55)
    - "Moynihan: The Bane of the Black New Class,", 1976 (Box-folder 16: 56)
    - "Trotsky in Perspective,", 1976 (Box-folder 16: 57)
    - "Socialism and Freedom," Colloquy in Trier, 1977 May 4 (Box-folder 17: 1)
    - "Detente and the Left After Afghanistan: Debate with Michael Harrington,", 1979 (Box-folder 17: 2)
    - Transcript of debate between Carl Gershman and M. Stanton Evans, Georgetown University, 1979 April 5 (Box-folder 17: 3)
    - "Selling Them the Rope," Commentary, 1979 April (Box-folder 17: 4)
    - "Background Paper on a New U.S. Organization on Africa,", 1980 February 8 (Box-folder 17: 5)
    - "American and Israeli Socialists--The Beginning of a Long Alliance,", undated (Box-folder 17: 6)
    - "The Future of Socialism,", undated (Box-folder 17: 7)
    - "The Palestinian Problem: A Radical View,", undated (Box-folder 17: 8)
    - "Socialism: The Diamond, Not the Dung,", undated (Box-folder 17: 9)
    - "Some Trends in the Jewish Student Movement," NJCRAC Plenary Session, undated (Box-folder 17: 10)
    - "Trotsky and the Trotskyites,", undated (Box-folder 17: 11)
    - Notes, 1969-1978 (Box-folder 17: 12)
  - WRITINGS BY OTHERS, 1969-1979 (Box 17)
    - Unidentified, 1970-1979 (Box-folder 17: 13)
    - Allen, Robert, 1972 (Box-folder 17: 14)
    - Blair, Eric, undated (Box-folder 17: 15)
    - Brandt, Willy, 1977 (Box-folder 17: 16)
    - Converse, Philip, Warren Miller, Jerrold Rusk, and Arthur Wolf, 1969 (Box-folder 17: 17)
    - Jackson, Henry, 1972 (Box-folder 17: 18)
    - Keyserling, Leon, 1969 (Box-folder 17: 19)
    - Laqueur, Walter, 1974 (Box-folder 17: 20)
    - Lenin, Vladimir as quoted by Yuri Annenkov in People and Portraits Vol. II, 1921 (Box-folder 17: 21)
    - Meany, George, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 17: 22)
    - Myrdal, Gunnar, 1969 (Box-folder 17: 23)
    - Rustin, Bayard, undated (Box-folder 17: 24)
    - Scheuer, Sidney, 1975 (Box-folder 17: 25)
    - Wattenberg, Ben, 1975 (Box-folder 17: 26)
  - COUNSELOR TO THE UNITED STATES REPRESENTATIVE TO THE UNITED NATIONS FILE, 1977-1984 (Boxes 18-21)
    - Correspondence, 1981-1984
      - General, 1981-1984
        - A-G, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 18: 1)
        - H-K, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 18: 2)
        - L-P, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 18: 3)
        - R-Z, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 18: 4)
      - Abrams, Elliott, 1983 (Box-folder 18: 5)
      - Arias-Stella, Javier, 1984 (Box-folder 18: 6)
      - Baumann, Fred, 1982 (Box-folder 18: 7)
      - Beichman, Arnold, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 18: 8)
      - Berger, Peter, 1982 (Box-folder 18: 9)
      - Biederman, Nota, 1983 (Box-folder 18: 10)
      - Bromber, Charney, 1982 (Box-folder 18: 11)
      - Brooks, Douglas, 1983 (Box-folder 18: 12)
      - Buckley, William, Jr., 1981 (Box-folder 18: 13)
      - Bukovsky, Vladimir, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 18: 14)
      - Cherne, Leo, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 18: 15)
      - Eliasz-Brantley, Eva, 1982 (Box-folder 18: 16)
      - Feulner, Edwin, Jr., 1982-1984 (Box-folder 18: 17)
      - Foxman, Abraham H., 1981-1982 (Box-folder 18: 18)
      - Gagnon, Yuan, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 18: 19)
      - Gay, Catherine, 1982 (Box-folder 18: 20)
      - Glikes, Erwin, 1982 (Box-folder 18: 21)
      - Godson, Roy, 1982 (Box-folder 18: 22)
      - Haig, Alexander, Jr., 1981 (Box-folder 18: 23)
      - Henkin, Alice, 1983 (Box-folder 18: 24)
      - Hellman, Ronald, 1984 (Box-folder 18: 25)
      - Hirsch, Dorothy, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 18: 26)
      - Horowitz, Irving, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 18: 27)
      - Hook, Sidney, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 18: 28)
      - Jaffe, Mimi, 1984 (Box-folder 18: 29)
      - Janitschek, Hans, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 18: 30)
      - Kaplan, Roger, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 18: 31)
      - Kembie, Penn, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 18: 32)
      - Kipper, Judith, 1982 (Box-folder 18: 33)
      - Kirkpatrick, Jeanne, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 18: 34)
      - Kline, Edward, 1982 (Box-folder 18: 35)
      - Korsa, Roseann, 1982 (Box-folder 18: 36)
      - Kurtz, Paul, 1982 (Box-folder 18: 37)
      - Lagos, Jaime, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 19: 1)
      - Lenkowsky, Leslie, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 19: 2)
      - Loeb, John, Jr., 1984 (Box-folder 19: 3)
      - Loebl, Eugen, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 19: 4)
      - Lookstein, Haskel, 1981 (Box-folder 19: 5)
      - Marcetic, Rastko, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 19: 6)
      - Mariaschin, Daniel, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 19: 7)
      - Marksbury, James, 1982 (Box-folder 19: 8)
      - Mihajlov, Mihajlo, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 19: 9)
      - Mirman, Marina, 1983 (Box-folder 19: 10)
      - Muravchik, Josh, 1981 (Box-folder 19: 11)
      - Musteikis, Antanass, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 19: 12)
      - O'Donovan, Declan, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 19: 13)
      - O'Neil, Edward, 1982 (Box-folder 19: 14)
      - Pavlovskis, Valdis, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 19: 15)
      - Payne, Irene, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 19: 16)
      - Perlmutter, Nathan, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 19: 17)
      - Peterson, Dave, 1982 (Box-folder 19: 18)
      - Pines, Burton Y., 1982 (Box-folder 19: 19)
      - Plax, Martin, 1982 (Box-folder 19: 20)
      - Podhoretz, Norman, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 19: 21)
      - Puddington, Arch, 1982 (Box-folder 19: 22)
      - Reich, Alan, 1981 (Box-folder 19: 23)
      - Ripoll, Carlos, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 19: 24)
      - Rockefeller, Nelson, Jr., 1982 (Box-folder 19: 25)
      - Roth, Neil, 1982 (Box-folder 19: 26)
      - Santana, Manuel, 1982 (Box-folder 19: 27)
      - Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr., 1982 (Box-folder 19: 28)
      - Seliger, Ralph, 1981 (Box-folder 19: 29)
      - Solzhenitsyn, Natalia, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 19: 30)
      - Svintsova, Olga, 1983 (Box-folder 19: 31)
      - Toby, Jackson, 1981 (Box-folder 19: 32)
      - Tsypkin, Mikhail, 1982 (Box-folder 19: 33)
      - Tyrell, R. Emmett, Jr., 1982-1983 (Box-folder 19: 34)
      - Weinstein, Allen, 1981 (Box-folder 19: 35)
      - Widetzky, Judi, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 19: 36)
      - Young, Stephen, 1984 (Box-folder 19: 37)
      - Unidentified, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 19: 38)
    - Central America writings, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 19: 39)
    - Economic and Social Council, 1982 (Box-folder 19: 40)
    - Event invitations, programs, and lists of attendees, 1981-1984
    - Franklin Delano Roosevelt Centennial Commission, 1982 (Box-folder 20: 1)
    - Gershman, Carl, 1981-1984
      - Notes, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 20: 2)
      - Press release statements, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 20: 3)
      - Statements, speeches, and addresses, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 20: 4)
    - Kirkpatrick, Jeane, 1981-1984
      - Press release statements, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 20: 5)
      - Statements, speeches, and addresses, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 20: 6)
    - Lemagne, Mario, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 20: 7)
    - Lichenstein, Charles, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 20: 8)
    - Meeting summary records, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 20: 9)
    - Mihajlov, Mihajlo, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 20: 10)
    - Young, Andrew, 1977-1978
      - Interview transcripts, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 20: 11)
      - Press release statements, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 20: 12)
      - Speeches, statements, and writings, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 20: 13)
      - Clippings, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 21: 1)
    - Press release statements, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 21: 2)
    - Printed matter, 1981-1984
      - General, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 21: 3)
      - Clippings, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 21: 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 21: 5)
  - SUBJECT FILE, 1961-1983 (Boxes 21-29)
    - Afghanistan, 1980 (Box-folder 21: 6)
    - Africa, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 21: 7)
    - American Jewish Congress, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 21: 8)
    - Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 21: 9)
    - Australia, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 21: 10)
    - Black Panthers, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 21: 11)
    - Britain, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 21: 12)
    - Chile, 1979 (Box-folder 21: 13)
    - China, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 21: 14)
    - Coalition for a Democratic Majority (CDM), 1974-1980
      - General, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 21: 15)
      - Jackson, Henry, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 21: 16)
      - Political Observer, 1975-1980 (Box-folder 21: 17)
    - Commentary, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 21: 18)
    - Common Cause, 1978 (Box-folder 22: 1)
    - Committee on New Alternatives in the Middle East, 1971 (Box-folder 22: 2)
    - Committee on Political Education (COPE), 1973-1979 (Box-folder 22: 3)
    - Committee on the Present Danger (CPD), 1977-1980 (Box-folder 22: 4)
    - Council on Religion and International Affairs (CRIA), 1978-1979 (Box-folder 22: 5)
    - Democracy International, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 22: 6)
    - Democratic Party, 1980 (Box-folder 22: 7)
    - Dissent, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 22: 8)
    - Dresser Industries, 1978 (Box-folder 22: 9)
    - Eastern Europe, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 22: 10)
    - Ethiopia, 1980 (Box-folder 22: 11)
    - Far Left, 1975-1980 (Box-folder 22: 12)
    - Freedom House, 1980 (Box-folder 23: 1)
    - Frontlash, 1977-1980 (Box-folder 23: 2)
    - Germany, 1980 (Box-folder 23: 3)
    - Gershman, Joseph, 1969 (Box-folder 23: 4)
    - Hammer, Armand, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 23: 5)
    - Harrington, Michael, 1973-1980 (Box-folder 23: 6)
    - Helsinki/Belgrade human rights, 1975-1978
      - General, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 23: 7)
      - Clippings, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 23: 8-9)
    - Indians for Democracy, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 23: 10)
    - Institute for Policy Studies, 1976-1978
      - General, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 23: 11)
      - Exploratory Project for Economic Alternatives, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 23: 12)
    - International Rescue Committee, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 24: 1)
    - Jamaica, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 24: 2)
    - Labor, 1968-1980
      - AFL-CIO, 1972-1979
        - General, 1972-1979 (Box-folder 24: 3)
        - Executive Council, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 24: 4)
        - Goldfinger, Nathaniel, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 24: 5)
        - Meany, George, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 24: 6)
        - Printed matter, 1970-1975
          - General, 1970-1975 (Box-folder 24: 7)
          - AFL-CIO News, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 24: 8)
          - Free Trade Union News, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 24: 9)
          - Free Trade Union News, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 24: 10)
          - Newsletters and releases, 1972-1979 (Box-folder 25: 1)
      - Communist influence, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 25: 2)
      - International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers (IAMAW), 1978-1980 (Box-folder 25: 3)
      - International Federation of Chemical and General Workers' Unions (ICF), 1971-1974 (Box-folder 25: 4)
      - International Federation of Petroleum and Chemical Workers (IFPCW), 1974 (Box-folder 25: 5)
      - International Labor Organization (ILO), 1973-1975 (Box-folder 25: 6)
      - Miscellaneous, 1971-1976 (Box-folder 25: 7)
      - Notes, 1971-1978 (Box-folder 25: 8)
      - Other radical groups and publications, 1976 (Box-folder 25: 9)
      - United Automobile Workers (UAW), 1973-1979 (Box-folder 25: 10)
      - United Mine Workers of America (UMWA), 1973-1977 (Box-folder 25: 11)
      - United Steelworkers of America (USWA), 1975-1978
        - General, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 25: 12)
        - February 8, 1977 election, 1975-1977
          - 1975-1977 (Box-folder 25: 13-14)
          - Anti-Sadlowski, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 26: 1)
          - Effect of media on campaign, 1976 (Box-folder 26: 2)
      - U.S. jobs, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 26: 3)
      - Printed matter, 1970-1975
        - General (Box-folder 26: 4)
        - Clippings, 1971-1980 (Box-folder 26: 5)
        - John Herling's Labor Letter, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 26: 6)
        - Serial issues, 1971-1979 (Box-folder 26: 7)
    - Labedz, Leopold, 1973-1980 (Box-folder 26: 8)
    - Madrid/Helsinki review, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 26: 9)
    - Martin, David, 1980 (Box-folder 26: 10)
    - McGovern, George, 1968-1977 (Box-folder 27: 1)
    - Menges, Constantine, 1980 (Box-folder 27: 2)
    - Middle East, 1969-1979 (Box-folder 27: 3)
    - Milstein, Tom, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 27: 4)
    - National Committee for Labor Israel (NCLI), 1972-1973 (Box-folder 27: 5)
    - New Directions, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 27: 6)
    - Nicaragua, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 27: 7)
    - Nuclear energy, 1980 (Box-folder 27: 8)
    - Poland, 1980 (Box-folder 27: 9)
    - Porter, Paul, 1979-1983 (Box-folder 27: 10)
    - Radio Liberty and Board for International Broadcast (BIB), 1976-1980 (Box-folder 27: 11)
    - Reuther, Victor, 1976 (Box-folder 27: 12)
    - Social Democrats, U.S.A., 1971-1980
      - Administrative file, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 27: 13)
      - Agenda, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 27: 14)
      - Andrei Sakharov campaign, 1974-1980 (Box-folder 27: 15)
      - Articles, speeches, and addresses, 1974-1980 (Box-folder 27: 16)
      - Minutes, 1974-1980 (Box-folder 27: 17)
      - New America, 1974 (Box-folder 27: 18)
      - Notes, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 27: 19)
      - Proposals and resolutions, 1974 (Box-folder 27: 20)
      - Young People's Socialist League (YPSL), 1971-1973 (Box-folder 27: 21)
      - Printed matter, 1972-1980
        - General, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 27: 22)
        - Notes, 1980 (Box-folder 27: 23)
    - Solarz, Stephen, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 27: 24)
    - Soviet Union, 1961-1980
      - 1961-1977 (Box-folder 28: 1)
      - 1978 (Box-folder 28: 2)
      - 1979 (Box-folder 28: 3)
      - 1980 (Box-folder 28: 4)
    - Tikkun, 1980 (Box-folder 28: 5)
    - Trilateral Commission, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 28: 6)
    - Union of Concerned Scientists, 1977 (Box-folder 28: 7)
    - University for Peace, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 28: 8)
    - Valladares, Armando, 1977-1980 (Box-folder 28: 9)
    - Vietnam, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 28: 10)
    - WEVD Radio Program, 1975 (Box-folder 28: 11)
    - World Without War Council, 1980 (Box-folder 28: 12)
    - Young Democrats, 1975 (Box-folder 29: 1)
    - Youth Committee for Peace and Democracy in the Middle East (YCPDME), 1969-1974 (Box-folder 29: 2)
    - Youth Institute for Peace in the Middle East (YIPME), 1980 (Box-folder 29: 3)
    - Zimbabwe, 1976-1979 (Box-folder 29: 4)
  - PRINTED MATTER, 1967-1981 (Boxes 29-31)
    - Clippings, 1967-1981
      - 1967 (Box-folder 29: 5)
      - 1968 (Box-folder 29: 6)
      - 1969 (Box-folder 29: 7)
      - 1970 (Box-folder 29: 8)
      - 1971 (Box-folder 29: 9)
      - 1972 (Box-folder 29: 10)
      - 1973 (Box-folder 29: 11)
      - 1974 (Box-folder 29: 12)
      - 1975 (Box-folder 29: 13)
      - 1976 (Box-folder 30: 1)
      - 1977 (Box-folder 30: 2)
      - 1978 (Box-folder 30: 3)
      - 1979 (Box-folder 30: 4)
      - 1980 (Box-folder 30: 5)
      - 1981 (Box-folder 30: 6)
    - Flyers, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 30: 7)
    - Pamphlets, 1970-1979 (Box-folder 30: 8)
    - Serial issues, 1969-1980
      - General, 1969-1980 (Box-folder 30: 9)
      - The American Zionist, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 31: 1)
      - Congress Bi-Weekly, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 31: 2)
      - Democratic Left, 1979 (Box-folder 31: 3)
      - Genesis 2, 1970 (Box-folder 31: 4)
      - Kehilath Jeshurun Bulletin, 1970 (Box-folder 31: 5)
  - SOUND RECORDING, 1979 (Box-folder 31: 6)
    Reel-to-reel recording of Carl Gershman debating M. Stanton Evans on capitalism, socialism, and democracy on April 5, 1979.